Christopher J. Warner II, Ph.D.

linkedin.com/in/chris-warner-II

chris-warner-ii.github.io
cwarner@berkeley.edu

Summary

Computational neuroscientist and biophysicist with a decade of expertise in data science and machine learning, I enjoy systems level thinking and excel in the intersection where technical ability and creativity are both required to bring various inputs together into algorithmic solutions.

Skills

Expertise: Building machine learning algorithms (neural networks, regression, classification, clustering), dynamical systems modelling, Graph Theory, Bayesian inference, visual neuroscience and image processing, time-series analysis Technology: Python, MATLAB, Labview, Mathematica, R, C++, Git, Docker, AWS, [Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Pandas, ...]

Experience

Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory

Oct 2023 - Present

Postdoctoral Researcher, Affiliate

- Characterized vocal complexity by computing Predictive Information on human speech TIMIT dataset
- Trained CNN model to classify spoken phoneme based on recorded speech spectrogram from TIMIT dataset

CODA Biotherapeutics

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022

Machine Learning Engineer, Consultant

- Delivered full ML algorithm to predict interactions between proteins and drugs including NLP implementation
- Interfaced with biologists to guide protein synthesis; incorporating their feedback to guide model development
- Transitioned project into production by leveraging cloud computing, containerization and process engineering

University of California, Berkeley

Sep 2011 - Sep 2019

Redwood Center for Theoretical Neuroscience, Graduate Student Researcher

- Pioneered retina-like image segmentation algorithm based on network modularity and anisotropic diffusion
- Built Bayesian latent variable model to infer unobserved cell assembly structure in spiking neural data
- Mentored undergrad students, guiding them in projects analyzing real world social network and global trade data

MIT, Lincoln Laboratory

Sep 2005 - Feb 2009

Advanced RF Techniques & Systems Group, Electrical Engineer

- Spearheaded radar program through hardware dev, software integration, testing, data collection, analysis and results
- Created statistical analysis pipeline to detect and classify moving targets under foliage using radar signature
- Tested, maintained and fielded electronic moving target simulator hardware units for radar system calibration

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Ph.D., Biophysics and Computational Neuroscience

Ohio State University

B.S., Physics

Berkeley, CA

Sep 2011 - Sep 2019

Columbus, OH

Sep 2001 - Jul 2005

Selected Publications

Warner, C., Ruda, K., Sommer, F.: Probabilistic latent variable model to detect structure in binary data. (2022)

Warner, C., Sommer, F.: A Model for Image Segmentation in Retina. (2020)

Extras

Creative & Technical: Self-produced an album of original songs I wrote, performed and recorded in Logic Self-starter: Operate a stealth startup exploring computational poetry and lyric analysis in phoneme space Intentional: Passionate about mindfulness and geared towards embracing challenge with a growth mindset